[Music]
hello and welcome to financial
mindfulness an exclusive webinar at icsc
director
joining us today is vinod philippe head
bank assurance of icici lumbar general
insurance
thank you very much vinod for joining us
today
i want you to talk to our viewers about
health insurance in particular
and just to start that conversation and
to put some context into that uh we're
currently going through a world
pandermaker
which of course has put a lot more focus
on health insurance than ever before
and i think most people would agree with
me that health insurance is an
important pillar of any sort of
financial plan
in fact an incomplete financial plan is
one where there isn't
sufficient coverage on health insurance
would you agree
yeah hi samuel thanks for the
opportunity it's uh grace address a
great addressing the team
uh see many people uh it's a very cliche
to say
insurance should be part of the
financial planning but health insurance
to an extent is very very unique
in the sense you look around
any hospitalization expenses today right
the annual increase the rate of
inflation in
hospitalization expense is going in
double or
more than double digits right the reason
is
most of these things the cost of
treatment is going up
the quality of treatment is going up the
technology and treatment is going up
all of this is adding up huge amount of
cost
to the end treatment of a disease or a
hospitalization
what this is also doing is
hospitalization unlike any other
financial products it's not a one-time
event
right okay you get hospitalized and then
you know you can rest assured for the
rest of your life you're not
you can't rest assured saying you will
not get admitted again
now hospitalization is a recurring
expenses in your life
the sad part of the story is why it
affects financially is
once you are into the hospital the
chances of recurring hospitalization as
you go
is very very high and that impacts your
savings
to a large extent right and that is why
of all the investment products or
protection products health insurance is
going to be
the most important aspect as one age
many a time you find friends colleagues
reaching out to you when it is already
too late
right so that balance is one of the most
important tool as far as
uh financial planning is concerned
indeed we'll note that
also another very popular sort of
sentiment that a lot of people would
resonate with is
in the corporate world most employees
are given
a corporate insurance policy
is that sufficient you'd imagine or one
should have a separate insurance policy
over and above the corporate policy
that's been provided to a salaried
employee
by his employer but two
uh ways to look at this okay uh
one how long are you going to stay
employed with that corporate
right because as long as you are staying
employed with that particular corporate
but to an extent protected by the
corporate right
second if you look at from a long-term
point of view
what happens after your employment with
the corporate all of us will get retired
at some point in time
your corporate cover also ceases with
your termination of your employment
and then suddenly when you come into the
market either you're too old
or your body is already sick that you
will not find
enough insurance coverage for yourself
and your family right
that's one part of the story the second
part of the story
is it's a cost item to the company
most of the companies today provide a 2
lakh or a 3 lakh
hospitalization cover for your families
in today's age and time 2 lakh and 3
lakhs
is hardly enough and we have enough and
more cases
where many employees come back and then
say i have exhausted my two legs and
three lacks limits
then what do i do right hence it's very
important
to always have not only as a backup
but also as a protection of your savings
to ensure a parallel cover along with a
corporate car
putting all the eggs in one basket is
not right right right
so we know that's of course got to do
with salaried employees what about
self-employed individuals so consultants
you know business owners entrepreneurs
most of us i'm counting myself and us
because that's pretty much the genre of
the corporate world that i
belong to we all have a contingency fund
which is really one of your
short-term financial goals any which
ways so if you do have a contingency
fund or an emergency fund
that would that money could of course be
used uh to fund your finance
fund your medical bills i'd imagine
would you still need a health cover even
if you have an emergency fund set up
contingency fund okay typically create
if it is going to be a one-time event
right
if it is going to be a recurring event
okay how much of a contingency fund you
have
it still not be enough because you don't
know
what is the sickness or what is the
reason for our hospitalization
when you're finally infected with right
right
like i'll give you a classic example
suppose god forbid
somebody has a heart attack right now
you will dip into a hospitalization
expense
and then you will take care of your
maybe you have three laps four lakh
surgery and then move on
right and then there is a repeat
hospitalization
maybe three years down the line four
years down the line
okay now what happens again you will
create one more contingency fund
right and then there is a third or
fourth sickness of another family member
yeah right so in uh i'm a
firm believer what is the cost of
creating a contingency fund
is that we the opportunity cost of
investing in a health insurance
right now for a specifically to say
you're one of the self-employed segments
right
an entrepreneur or whoever when you
write even a 5000 rupees check to a
hospital
it pinches you right it's a question of
transferring that risk for a paltry
premium
by paying say 10 000 rupees or 15 000
rupees
okay am i saving or the return which i
might getting by paying that 50 000
is it going to be high or low
right well at the end of the day what
are you saving you're saving some 15 000
bucks in today's age 15 000 rupees for a
family is nothing
okay but what are you creating as a
corpus you are wanting to create a
corpus of six thousand
sorry six like seven likely like ten
likes now why
there is an insurance company who's an
expert in the subject matter
stay safe let that risk be burned by
somebody else
right so that's my advice to all the
self-employed targets
and i think you know the government also
resonates with that right there's
obviously a strong push towards
encouraging individuals to invest in
health insurance and it is march it's
that time of the year when i cannot help
but ask you
are there any tax saving benefits if you
go out there
and invest in health insurance so or
rather on a health insurance premium
are there any tax saving benefits here
tax saving is definitely a huge
inducement to buy
uh i don't deny that but i have a larger
point of view
health insurance is one of anybody's
largest investment
return that you will ever fetch i'll
give you a very a simple mathematics
i you know early question you trust
about i touched upon
what is going to be your average premium
right 15 000 yeah
suppose a guy comes in and joins a
health insurance a young guy 35 year old
let's assume he paid 15 000 rupees and
bottom insurance
right for next 10 years assuming that
the inflation of the premium and et
cetera et cetera goes up
assuming that the next 10 years he pays
an average premium of say 20
20 000 rupees for next 10 years right
now 35 guy
year old guy has become say 45 in the 10
years
now what is the chances of a
hospitalization happening
in that family in a time 10 years time
much higher right in 10 years time frame
how much do they have paid in 10 years
premium 2 lakhs
yeah in 10 years time pay one visit to
the hospital and come back
how much of money he or she would have
saved
and the number of hospitalization goes
up to letters you too
yeah you have paid only two lakhs for
ten years but what you would have said
is a four likes or a five lakhs
yeah that's point number one point
number two many instances when a
customer has got hospitalized for some
reason or the other it's equivalent to a
non-performing asset
our bodies once it becomes sick
we are technically like a non-performing
asset
you will not get insurance cover in the
market at all
that sounds very depressing but okay i
guess i get your point there
it's crude but that's a fact of the
matter yeah yeah let's extend this
argument to
a guy the same guy 35 year old stays
invested for 20 years
he would have paid 4 lakhs or maybe five
lakhs yeah
chances of hospitalization in his family
in a span of 20 years three times four
times
and every time every time he gets
hospitalized
today you go to the best of the best
hospitals you don't get out without a
two lakhs bill
you look at cobit in a covered kind of
scenario one member of the family
infects the rest of the family members
it's a cohabitation of the disease
so two lakhs per member
okay and that is eight lakhs then what
do you do
so by just paying say two lakhs over a
period of say 10 years or 20 year time
frame
what you get in return is almost 2x 3x
of what you would have actually paid and
similarly you come until age
today who is the biggest buyer
or who is seeking insurance are those
guys
already grown old hmm you and i today
are looking for parental cover
why when those parents our parents were
young they didn't buy
but the question is you and i are today
young when we become
60 or 70 do you want your children to
hunt for parental color
that's the question right you know i
think that's
a very uh valid point you've made right
especially the pandemic has
showed us very harsh reality that life
is truly very unpredictable it's not
about being 70 and getting sick we have
25 year olds
that are now falling ill of course uh
before the pandemic if you told a 25
year old you need to get in
health insurance they probably disagree
with you
if you told a 45 year old you need to
get health insurance a conversation
would be very different but let's just
for the sake of our viewers and hoping
that people understand this better
tell us what in your mind is the right
age
to buy health insurance i know the
earlier the better right
i don't think there's a there's nothing
but at the right age
okay but there's always a wrong age
okay the wrong age is anything above 45
is the wrong age to buy
because the problem is in a 45 you would
want a high cover meaning you are
looking for a 25
cover of 50 lakh cover but your body is
not
is not good enough for the insurance
company to take that risk of
right so earlier the better is a cliche
but anytime today even today when our
our data is a lumbar specifically data
a large part of the data will be very
very surprised
are less than 45 year olds
okay and those because of lifestyle
diseases
lack of exercise lack of fitness
whatever you might want to call it
right the incidences of the less than 45
year olds getting hospitalized
is very very high point number one
the average claim of a customer who is
less than 45
is far higher than a customer who is
above 40. i'm going for a run right now
yeah you should yes sir right
so uh even today
some of the younger guys have started uh
you know
telling us about diabetes yeah
hypertension
right and when it starts hitting you at
a very very young age
you will never get a cover in the market
you will still be dependent
on some government schemes for you to
wrestle around and give you a protection
come
right so you don't know so don't wait
for the moment to happen and then look
for a cover by the time it's just too
late
it's too late yeah it's right start
today i mean that's the advice we can
give you if you don't already have it
please go out there and buy health
insurance it doesn't matter how old you
are
you've got to get onto onto onto the
track pretty quickly
uh we know of course uh we live in a
country where it's about
families right it's about your children
it's about your parents it's almost
hamsa
satay and everything so help me
understand this
individual health insurance versus group
health insurance
how do those two compare with each other
okay uh i think the question will need
to be slightly reframed
since a retail versus a group card
right uh say retail is
a one size fit for all available to all
customers of an insurance company
it does not distinguish between channel
it does not distribute between a
particular customer segment etc etc
yeah there are uh segments which
a retail product caters to right
the big difference in a group is
customization
right now that customization is very
very unique
okay because you try to understand
a cohort of customers and tailor make a
cover
for that cohort of customers what it
does is
you are riding on a channel's knowledge
and understanding of a customer
hence that information is going to be
very very supreme when you are
constructing a product and delivering it
to the channel
the case in point to say i say is a
security we know
the premium quality customers of ics
securities
right we know the age segments they have
been
dealing with isis and securities for
years together
right so the knowledge about the
customer
is so high right
hence i am able to construct the product
which is very very comprehensive it is
very competitive
and it's very convenient to buy
right that i'm able to construct all the
three
you will find some of these features
would be completely at a variance to
what you might
be offered on the read so
right so in case a customer
depending again about which channel
partner is offering
i would always recommend that today in
the marketplace
you should look for a group offering
cover because if you are tied to a
particular channel partner
you will generally find the offer that
you get from the channel partner is
going to be very very supreme
because the channel partner assumes the
role of a customer and negotiates hard
with insurance company and say
hey this is what my customers want right
right so from entire cohort of customers
i'm picking up cherry picking a set of
customers and say these are my set of
customers
this is the ask of my customers hence
i'm able to tailor make a
product and give it to the set of
customers which will be very difficult
in the retail salary because i'll get
everybody there
right and so we know while it is a lot
more superior it's tailor-made are there
any more unique sort of features
of a group health insurance plan that
you'd like to tell our audience
yeah so there are one which is already
on with ics securities
um
one of the key features like for
instance the bleeding bridge
so in a health insurance it's not that
you'll get a coverage from day one
there are certain illnesses which will
get covered
most of the retail products in the
market has a 24 month waiting period
like classic example earlier sinusitis
okay those kind of very common element
those get covered only after 24 months
right in a group construct we have said
for icc securities customers
this will not be 24 months but this will
be only 12 months
right so by entering into this segment
you are able to give that benefit to the
set of customer
spices securities that's a big ask
then what happens you just wait for one
year there after the entire book is open
for you
right so that is one second
there are certain relaxations in terms
of service levels there are certain
taxations in terms of
onboarding a certain customer so this
the the deep analysis which i might do
of a retail customer i may not do it
with a group customer right right
that's the second uh distinction the
third distinction obviously is the
pricing part
right you will find the pricing to be
far far competitive than the retail
offering
because i've tailor made the product to
suit the requirements
of a particular segment of isis
so you will find convenience
comprehensiveness of the product
and the competitiveness of production so
icc security is a complete online
platform it's entirely so i have my
customer need not fill any proposal
forms no physical forms
you can log into a section buy the form
get the instant policy and move on it's
a lot more convenient as well
so while i want to talk a little bit
more about group health plans uh
can we also buy it for our parents or is
it just restricted to individuals
okay so you can buy it for parents um
obviously it comes with uh you know
what is the level of their health okay
where are they places whereas health is
concerned
so today you have a product segment
there are two set of product segments
which are there for
especially what we call a senior
citizens okay
a customer who's got a very clean health
he can get a normal health in charge
right any hospitalization cover cetera
a customer who does not have
a great health meaning he's already
suffering from certain diabetes or
hypertension etc etc
or what we call it insurance parlance is
pre-existing
right for those customers also we have a
wellness product
right we may not be able to cover the
entire hospitalization experience
but we have put together product which
at least will try to
help him prevent the hospitalization
right for instance most of these
customers when you spine
they do a annual health checkup right
right
and they don't do it to a full extent
because of costing et cetera et cetera
you compromise on certain tests oh said
no no i will owe you this much test
by buying this product he doesn't need
to worry i will take care of 360 degree
of all his tests
right then i have a doctor on call
at any point in time you can reach out
to my doctor i have an emergency
uh support system available for such
custom
and in the event something happens
okay i even from a hospital daily cash
okay right from day one for the number
of days he
or she gets hospital so for instance i
have a limit of 4000 rupees a day 5000
rupees a day
depending upon the concept of the
product i paying for the number of days
up to a maximum of 30 days in a year so
that
product construct what we call as a zero
cost to the customer right
so every and all of these customers who
have an illness
or sick in the body all of these
customers today incur
these expenses individuals okay
and you add a tax cut saving element to
this
net net the customer doesn't pay
anything from this book that's scary
yeah so we have created that product
suit also for a customer who is
not on this pink obviously so lots of
frills that of course would make it very
uh you know superior as compared to
individual
health plans uh we know that we're
running out of time but very quickly
on the group health plan is it a
lifetime renewability
what is the uh what is the rules and
regulations in place right now with
renewability
okay the rules are exactly the same as
what you have on the retail side
right the only difference is the mem
the customer who's got attached to a
group
he has to stay invested in that group or
he needs to continue to have the
relationship for life long
okay right as long as that relationship
for instance if a customer has come to
as a group customer
to through icc securities as long as
he's part of the icsf family
i say say securities family he will
continue to get a lifelong recovery
so he has to be part of it but there are
relaxations where he can switch for
instance tomorrow
he can move he can choose any of our
retail product that is still an offering
but my senses
even then a customer today will get a
lifelong review but the case
the point is he needs to get himself
insured for health insurance
right thereafter lifelong renewable
takes care
so individual group this is a compulsion
you have to understand as you as young
and old that
health insurance is a very important
pillar of
fine a sound financial plan but
hopefully we've answered a lot of the
queries that the audience could have
potentially had but
out of time now but no thanks to tan for
joining us have a great evening thank
you thanks thanks
thank you so much